

Vladislava Leykin

Experienced Software Engineer

♀ Linz, Austria

4 +4369010449996

www.linkedin.com/in/vlada-leykin/

@ vlada.leykin@gmail.com

Strengths

Responsible Transparent Accurate Solution oriented Proactive

Languages English

Full professional proficiency

German

A2 Neveau Limited working proficiency

Russian

Mother tongue

Hebrew

Bilingual proficiency

Skills

Javascript

Typescript
React
Web development
CI/CD
Git
C#
Clean code
Agile
Mentorship

Multinational team

Interests

Traveling
Gardening
Yoga
Graphic Design
Care about environment
Sewing
Books

About me

My passion for Software Development found expression as I studied Computer Science and later worked 7 years as a Software Engineer. I made the path to Senior Software Developer and eventually I was leading a team as a Software Architect.

I mastered the art of working with dozens of developers on the same codebase, delivering high quality features in the shortest time that affect the lives of millions of people around the world. After big career growth my life took me on a journey through parenthood and relocation to another country, language and culture.

Currently, I'm looking for a part-time software engineering position where I could express my skills and balance with the parental-responsibilities.

Professional Experience

Carrier break Feb 2022 - current

My career break started after my husband signed a contract with an Austrian company Dynatrace. My family moved to Linz in June 2022. My daughter turned 2 at this time. Since our relocation I've been balancing between maternity duties, relocation tasks, learning German and recapturing my professional skills by doing hands-on project.

Senior Software Engineer Wix.com

Dec 2015 - Feb 2022 Tel Aviv, Israel

At first I was part of the Wix Academy project for junior developers - an hands-on training of modern Web development, including HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, tests and Git.

My first years in the Wix Editor departement I worked in a big codebase written in Javascript and React. I've improved performance of the key features, reduced the code complexity and increased quality. I mastered the art of writing clean and readable code, delivering it with continuous integration, monitoring, refactoring, conducting experiments on new features, writing tests, giving and receiving a code review.

Last 3 years of my work at Wix I was part of the Wix Editor Platform Team. We created and maintained the infrastructure for Applications to make it possible to extend Wix Editor abilities in the fastest way. We managed Platform and Editor SDK repositories, created documentation and worked together with Product Managers and our customers to come up with practical and yet integral solutions. In my latest position as a Software Architect I participated in a quarter planning, created backlog, trained and mentored a joined team from the Wix Ukraine office.

Software Developer Elbit Systems

Nov 2013 - Dec 2015 Tel Aviv, Israel

I've developed fully automatized test application (C#) for PCB components that dramatically improved coverage and performance, and reduced operator involvement to minimum. Application consists of an automation engine, GUI based management and reports modules.

Education

BSc in Computer Science Tel Aviv Academic College

2011-2015

In my study I kept the trend toward Big Data and NoSQL, experienced Hadoop, Spark with integration to Kafka. Other backend specialties are Node.js, Java and MongoDB NoSQL databases. Client side programming with JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap.